Inventory of the Stolen Years: video tape
Hoover Institution Archives
Stolen Years: video tape
1999
99043
1 item (6 manuscript boxes) (2.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Videotaped raw footage of interviews with historians and Soviet forced labor camp survivors, relating to forced labor camps in the Soviet Union. Used as background material for the program. Program produced by the Blackwell Corporation and broadcast by the Public Broadcasting Service.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1999.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Videotaped raw footage of interviews with historians and Soviet forced labor camp survivors conducted between 1996 to 1998, relating to forced labor camps in the Soviet Union. Used as background material for the program Stolen Years (1999) directed by Bruce Young and produced by Neal B. Freeman and Jennifer Law Young. Program produced by the Blackwell Corporation and broadcast by the Public Broadcasting Service.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Forced labor--Soviet Union.; Videotapes.; Blackwell Corporation (Washington, D.C.)
Collection Contents
- Video recordings on Betacam SP tapes, 1996-1998 (Box 1-6)
  - Joffe, Nadezhda A., Undated (Box 1: 1-2)
  - Joffe, Nadezhda A., 1996 January 6 (Box 1: 3-4)
  - 1996 February 15 (Box 1 :5-6)
  - Razgon, Lev, 1996 February 15 (Box 1-2: 7-9)
  - Vilensky, Simon, 1996 February 18 (Box 2: 10-12)
  - 1996 February 18 (Box 2: 13-14)
  - Vilensky, Simon, 1996 February 19 (Box 2: 15-16)
  - 1996 February 20 (Box 3: 17-18)
  - Glinka, Elena, 1996 February 21 (St. Petersburg) (Box 3: 19-23)
  - Petkevich, Tamara, 1996 February 22 (Box 3-4: 24-26)
  - Simon Velinsky, Peter and at the "Mask of Grief Memorial,", 1996 June 18 (Box 4: 27)
  - Myasnikova, Paulina, 1996 June 18 (Box 4: 28-31)
  - Demant, Peter, 1996 June 19 (Box 4-5: 32-34)
  - Getman, Nikolay, 1997 January 7, 16 (Box 5-6: 35-38)
  - Bien, George, undated (Box 6: 39-44)
  - Conquest, Robert, 1998, April 13 (Stanford) (Box 6: Unnumbered)